Brainard, Charles Henry, 1817-1885. Charles Henry Brainard papers, 1795-1884 (MS Am 889.14-889.16): Guide.
Charles Henry Brainard papers,
1795-1884 and undated.
Houghton Library, Harvard College Library, Harvard University
MS Am 889.14
MS Am 889.15
MS Am 889.16
Brainard, Charles Henry, 1817-1885.
4 volumes (.5 linear ft.)
Autograph album (1858-1884), a letter book (1855-1883), and a scrapbook of letters and autographs (1795-1857 and undated) of American print dealer, publisher, and historian, Charles Henry Brainard.
No accession number. Bequest of Evert Jansen Wendell; received: 1918.
There are no restrictions on physical access to this material.
Brainard (1817-1885) was an historian, print dealer, and publisher as C.H. Brainard Publishing Co., in Boston, Massachusetts. In 1885 he wrote: John Howard Payne, a biographical sketch of the author of "Home, sweet home", ...
Arranged in call-number order:
MS Am 889.14: Autograph album
MS Am 889.15: Letter book
MS Am 889.16: Scrapbook and index
Includes three volumes: an autograph album (1858-1884), a letter book (1855-1883), and a scrapbook of letters and autographs (1795-1857 and undated).
The autograph album (MS Am 889.14) contains autograph quotations or sentiments, signed, from Matilda Goddard, Jacqueline Pendleton, Rufus Dawes, S. E. Sewall, Thaddeus Hyatt (dated 3 Apr. 1860 at the Washington jail), Anna E. Dickinson, W. H. H. Murray, and others; with a photograph of Hyatt, signed, addressed to Brainard.
The letter book (MS Am 889.15) contains letters to Brainard written to Brainard from John Whittier, Charles Sumner, William Burleigh, Celia Burleigh, Rufus Dawes, George Ripley, and others; with a portrait print of Ripley.
The scrapbook (MS Am 889.16) contains letters, few to Brainard, and cut-out signatures from Noah Webster, Washington Allston, Jared Sparks, John Pierpont, and others. The autographs of Eliza Leslie, John Whittier, Thomas Read, Horace Greeley, and others are accompanied by portrait prints. A typescript list of autographs was inserted the front, now removed to separate folder.
- Brainard, Charles Henry, 1817-1885. Autograph album, 1858-1884., 1 volume.
  Contains autograph poems, quotations, or sentiments, signed and dated. Most often the text is copied and is not original to the author. Also includes a carte-de-visite photograph.
  Includes the following items [blank pages have not been listed]:
  - Mackay, Charles, 1814-1889. Returning messengers: autograph manuscript poem, 1858., Page 1
  - Cary, Phoebe, 1824-1871. Trust: autograph manuscript poem, 1867., Page 2
  - Janvier, Francis De Haes, 1817-1885. Alas! That friendship's fragile flowers [first line]: autograph manuscript poem, 1858., Page 3
  - Bailey, Gamaliel, 1807-1859. What to other men would be no duty [first line]: autograph manuscript, 1859., Page 5
  - Dawes, Rufus, 1803-1859. A farewell: autograph manuscript poem, 1858., Pages 7-8
  - Giddings, Joshua R. (Joshua Reed), 1795-1864. God and nature [first line]: autograph manuscript, 1858., Page 9
  - Bodichon, Barbara Leigh Smith, 1827-1891. A love of nature [first line]: autograph manuscript, 1858., Page 11
  - Southworth, Emma Dorothy Eliza Nevitte, 1819-1899. Asperations are prophecies: autograph manuscript, 1858., Page 13
  - Mario, Jessie White, 1832-1906. Endurance is the crowning quality [first line]: autograph manuscript, 1859., Page 15
  - Tindleton, Jacqueline. Educate your women, as they have authority to be respected [first line]: autograph manuscript, 1859., Page 17
  - Sewall, Samuel E. (Samuel Edmund), 1799-1888. Justice is the everlasting and immutable [first line]: autograph manuscript, 1860., Page 19
  - Sewall, H. W. Life's garlands fade and fall too fast [first line]: autograph manuscript poem, undated., Page 21
  - J.T. Cognacq (Paris), photographer.; Thaddeus Hyatt: carte-de-visite photograph, 1863., Page 23
    Recto signed by Hyatt and inscribed: "La Rochelle 14. Dec. '63."
    Verso inscribed: "Presented to Ch. H. Brainard by his sincere friend Thaddeus Hyatt."
  - Hyatt, Thaddeus. He that is true to himself is true to God [first line]: autograph manuscript, 1860., Page 25
  - Garrison, William Lloyd, 1805-1879. To Thaddeus Hyatt: autograph manuscript poem, 1860., Page 26
  - Tilton, Theodore, 1835-1907. Infidelity is the religion of [first line]: autograph manuscript, undated., Page 27
  - Barry, Charles A., 1830-1892. F. H. B. In paradise-: autograph manuscript poem, 1862., Page 29
  - Kimball, Josiah F. As wanderers seek some mill they oft have tasted [first line]: autograph manuscript poem, 1861., Page 31
  - Whittier, M. F. What is man, or the son of man? [first line]: autograph manuscript, 1861., Page 33
  - Slack, Charles W. (Charles Wesley), 1825-1885. Weak men have wishes; strong men wills [first line]: autograph manuscript, 1861., Page 35
  - Goddard, Matilda. Our future may seem defeat but [first line]: autograph manuscript, 1862., Page 37
  - Hunt, Harriet H. God's completeness round out incompleteness [first line]: autograph manuscript, 1862., Page 39
  - Sargent, John T. (John Turner), 1808-1877. There is no power outside of the church [first line]: autograph manuscript, 1862., Page 41
  - Carpenter, F. B. (Francis Bicknell), 1830-1900. The possibilities opened up to the human family by a true [first line]: autograph manuscript, 1864., Page 43
  - Joyce, Robert Dwyer, 1836-1883. Thou ran she 'till she plucked his gown again [first line]: autograph manuscript poem, 1878., Page 45
  - Dickinson, Anna E. (Anna Elizabeth), 1842-1932. All the world's a stage, & all the [first line]: autograph manuscript, undated., Page 47
  - Burleigh, Celia, 1825-1875. The home is to each human soul the [first line]: autograph manuscript, 1871., Page 49
  - Owen, John, 1806-1882. To John Greenleaf Whittier: On the seventieth anniversary of his birthday December 17, 1877: autograph manuscript poem, 1878., Page 51
  - Cook, Joseph. Duty done is the soul's fireside [first line]: autograph manuscript, 1878., Page 53
  - Trowbridge, J. T. (John Townsend), 1827-1916. Religion is no leaf of faded green: autograph manuscript poem, 1878., Page 55
  - Whiffle, E. P. In all the autographs [first line]: autograph manuscript, 1879., Page 57
  - Perkins, Frederic B. (Frederic Beecher), 1828-1899. As I am no poet, as facts [first line]: autograph manuscript, 1879., Page 59
  - Shillaber, B. P. (Benjamin Penhallow), 1814-1890. An art creed: autograph manuscript poem, 1879., Page 61
  - Murray, W. H. H. (William Henry Harrison), 1840-1904. Character dictates destiny [first line]: autograph manuscript, 1878., Page 63
  - Clemmer, Mary, 1839-1884. Tis not the thought that Jesus died: autograph manuscript poem, 1881., Page 69
    Also with autograph of Gustavus A. Somerby pasted to page.
  - Gallagher, William D. (William Davis), 1808-1894. The brown thrush: autograph manuscript poem, 1882., Page 71-73
    With a clipping which includes The brown thrush.
  - Burnett, Jerome C., 1833-1891. Magnolia: autograph manuscript poem, 1884., Page 75
  - Rice, Albert. Life's autumn: autograph manuscript poem, 1884., Page 79
- Brainard, Charles Henry, 1817-1885. Letter book, 1855-1883., 1 volume.
  Letters sent to Brainard.
  Includes the following items:
  - Whittier, John Greenleaf, 1807-1892. Letters to Charles Henry Brainard, 1864-1878 and undated., (1) - (12)
  - Sumner, Charles, 1811-1874. Letters to Charles Henry Brainard, 1855-1870 and undated., (13) - (28)
  - Phillips, Wendell, 1811-1884. Letters to Charles Henry Brainard, 1876 and undated., (29) - (30)
  - Unidentified correspondent. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1855., (31)
  - Seward, William Henry, 1801-1872. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1855., (32)
  - Smith, Gerrit, 1797-1874. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1860., (33)
  - Seward, William Henry, 1801-1872. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1859., (34)
  - Giddings, Joshua Reed, 1795 - 1864. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1856., (35)
  - Durkee, Charles, 1805-1870. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1860., (36)
  - Giddings, Joshua Reed, 1795 - 1864. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1850., (37)
  - Wilson, Henry, 1812-1875. Letters to Charles Henry Brainard, 1850., (38)
  - Newman, John. Letters to Charles Henry Brainard, 1858., (39)
  - Burleigh, Celia, 1825-1875. Letters to Charles Henry Brainard, 18??, (40)
    Letter signed "Celia M. Burr".
  - Burleigh, William Henry, 1812-1871. Letters to Charles Henry Brainard, 1869., (41) - (42)
  - Burleigh, Celia, 1825-1875. Letters to Charles Henry Brainard, 1869-1875., (43) - (57)
  - Tilton, Theodore, 1835-1907. Letters to Charles Henry Brainard, 1860-1863., (58) - (59)
  - Cary, Phoebe, 1824-1871. Letters to Charles Henry Brainard, 1867 and undated., (60) - (61)
  - Clemmer, Mary, 1839-1884. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1877., (62)
  - Dickinson, Anna E. (Anna Elizabeth), 1842-1932. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1869., (63)
  - Dawes, Rufus, 1803-1859. Letters to Charles Henry Brainard, 1849-1853., (64) - (66)
  - Read, Thomas Buchanan, 1822-1872. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1848., (67)
  - Unidentified correspondent. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1870., (68)
  - ?, Richard. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1860., (69)
  - Reilly, Thomas Devin. Letters to Charles Henry Brainard, 1853., (70)
  - Emerson, Ralph Waldo, 1803-1882 Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1838., (71)
  - Winship. Letters to Charles Henry Brainard, 1871., (72)
  - Shillaber, B. P. (Benjamin Penhallow), 1814-1890. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1877., (73)
  - Bodichon, Barbara Leigh Smith, 1827-1891. Letters to Charles Henry Brainard, undated., (74) - (76)
  - Mario, Jessie White, 1832-1906. Letters to Charles Henry Brainard, 1859 and undated., (77) - (78)
  - Hosmer, Harriet Goodhue, 1830-1908. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, undated., (79)
  - Cushman, Charlotte, 1816-1876 Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, undated., (80)
  - Southworth, Emma Dorothy Eliza Nevitte, 1819-1899. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1849., (81)
  - Unidentifed correspondent. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, undated., (82)
  - King, Susan Petigru, 1824-1875. Letters to Charles Henry Brainard, 1855-1869., (83) - (85a)
  - Johnston, Thomas M. Letters to Charles Henry Brainard, 1859-1860., (86) - (88)
  - Pendleton, John S. (John Strother), 1802-1868. Letters to Charles Henry Brainard, 1858 and undated., (89) - (93)
  - Baker, E.K. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1849., (94)
  - Morehead, C. S. (Charles Slaughter), 1802-1868. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1849., (95)
  - Niles, M. A. H. (Mark Antony Haskell). Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1845., (96)
  - Toombs, Robert Augustus, 1810-1885. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1854., (97)
  - Millan, W.H.? Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1855., (98)
  - Pearce, James Alfred, 1804-1862. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1858., (99)
  - Lowell, Charles, 1782-1861. Letters to Charles Henry Brainard, 1859., (100) - (101)
  - Meade? Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1859., (102)
  - Slack, Charles W. (Charles Wesley), 1825-1885. Letters to Charles Henry Brainard, 1861-1864., (103) - (104)
  - Koehler, S. R. (Sylvester Rosa), 1837-1900. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1869., (105)
  - Carpenter, F. B. (Francis Bicknell), 1830-1900. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1867., (106)
  - Bellows, A. F. (Albert Fitch), 1829-1883. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 187?, (107)
  - Unidentified correspondent. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1876., (108)
  - Rogers, John. Letters to Charles Henry Brainard, 1874 and undated., (109) - (110)
  - Ripley, George, 1802-1880. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1864., (111)
  - Unidentified correspondent. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1879., (112)
  - Whittier, John Greenleaf, 1807-1892. Letters to Charles Henry Brainard, 1881-1882., (113) - (115)
  - Loring, George Bailey, 1817-1891. Letters to Charles Henry Brainard, 1881., (116) - (117)
  - Whittier, John Greenleaf, 1807-1892. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1882., (118)
  - B[ ], Joel. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1882., (119)
  - Corcoran, W. W. (William Wilson), 1798-1888. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1882., (120)
  - Sprague, Kate Chase, 1840-1899. Letters to Charles Henry Brainard, 1883., (121)
  - Manuscript list of autograph signatures and addresses, undated., (122)
  - Henry, J. A. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1883., (123)
  - Gitt, D.L. Letters to Charles Henry Brainard, undated., (124)
  - Tuttle, Edmund B. (Edmund Bostwick), 1815-1881. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, undated., (125)
  - Walker, Jason. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, undated., (126)
  - Smith, Azariah. Letters to Charles Henry Brainard, 1882., (127)
  - Foley, Margaret F. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1858., (128)
  - Snelling, William Joseph, 1804-1848. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1845., (129)
  - Carleton, Will, 1845-1912. Letters to Charles Henry Brainard, 1884., (130) - (131)
  - Read, Harriet Denison. Letters to Charles Henry Brainard, 1881., (132) - (133)
  - Foley, Margaret F. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1858., (134)
  - Chapman. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, undated., (135)
  - Sumner, Charles, 1811-1874. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1856., (136)
- Brainard, Charles Henry, 1817-1885. Scrapbook, 1795-1857., 2 volumes.
  Primarily letters, autographs, and portrait prints sometimes with annotations by Brainard.
  Typescript list of autographs was inserted at front of volume, now removed to separate folder.
  - Seated woman and child: engraving, undated., Page 1
  - Phobe Cary: portrait print, undated., Page 4
  - Webster, Noah, 1758-1843. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1830., Page 6
  - Allston medal: print, undated., Page 7
  - Allston, Washington, 1779-1843. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1837., Page 8
  - Sarah Stearns: manuscript poem, undated., Page 9
    Includes braided lock of human hair.
  - Dawes, Richard, 1793-1867. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1854., Page 10
    Also Includes: Note from Emma Dorothy Eliza Nevitte Southworth to Charles Henry Brainard, undated.
  - Russell, John. Letter to James?, 1810., Page 14
  - Gallatin, Albert, 1761-1849. Letter to George P. Stark?, 1847., Page 18
  - Brig. Genl. Daniel Morgan: engraving, undated., Page 19
    Includes: Morgan, Daniel, 1736-1802. Autograph.
  - Multiple items., Page 20
    Includes:
    Glover, John. Autograph.
    Morgan, Daniel, 1736-1802. Receipt, 1798.
    Page has top portion torn away.
  - Multiple items., Page 22
    Easton, J.H. Autograph.
    ? from U. S. Navy Department. Autograph.
    Priestly, J. Autograph.
    Vance, Joseph, 1786-1852. Autograph.
    Clay, Henry, 1777-1852. Autograph.
    Force, Peter, 1790-1868. Autograph.
  - Major General Arthur St. Clair: engraving, undated., Page 23
    Includes: St. Clair, Arthur, 1734-1818. Autograph.
  - Multiple items., Page 24
    St. Clair, Arthur, 1734-1818. Autograph.
    Randolph, Peyton, 1721-1775. Autograph.
    Illegible autograph.
    Eliott, Jesse D. (Jesse Duncan), 1782-1845. Autograph.
    Southard, Samuel L. (Samuel Lewis), 1787-1842.
    Webster, Daniel, 1782-1852. Autograph.
  - Multiple items., Page 26
    Irving, Washington, 1783-1859. Autograph.
    Cooper, James Fenimore, 1789-1851. Autograph.
    Everett, Edward, 1794-1865. Autograph.
    Briggs, George N. (George Nixon), 1796-1861. Autograph.
    Seaton, William Winston, 1785-1866. Autograph.
    Espy, James P. (James Pollard), 1785-1860. Autograph.
    Nichol, J.P. (John Pringle), 1804-1859. Autograph.
    Davis, John Wesley, 1799-1859. Autograph.
    Hill, Isaac, 1789-1851. Autograph.
  - Multiple items., Page 27
    Custis, George Washington Parke, 1781-1857. Autograph.
    Ujhari, Ladislaus? Autograph.
    Fillmore, Milliard, 1800-1874. Autograph.
    Dawes, Rufus, 1803-1859. Autograph note.
  - Multiple items., Page 28
    Whittier, John Greenleaf, 1807-1892. Autograph.
    Part of fifty dollar banknote with illegible signature.
    Halleck, Fitz-Greene, 1790-1867. Autograph.
    Morris, George Pope, 1802-1864. Autograph.
    Pierpont, John, 1785-1866. Autograph.
    Sigourney, L.H. (Lydia Howard), 1791-1865. Autograph.
    Bryant, William Cullen, 1794-1878. Autograph.
    Gallagher, William D. (William Davis), 1808-1894. Autograph.
  - Multiple items., Page 29
    Stearns, Geo. L. (George Luther), 1809-1867. Autograph, includes address, Medford, Massachusetts.
    Manley, John R? Autograph, includes address, 24 Doch Square.
    Woodman, Horatio, 1821-1879. Autograph, includes address, 25 R.R. Exchange.
    Dudley, E.G? Autograph, includes address, 20 Court Street.
  - Clay, H. Autograph., Page 30
  - Sigourney, L.H. (Lydia Howard), 1791-1865. The Butterfly: autograph manuscript poem., Page 31
  - Lyon, Caleb, 1822-1875. Embathed in thoughts divine my soul [first line]: autograph manuscript poem; Washington D.C., 1848 February 19., Page 32
  - Gould, Hannah Flagg, 1789-1865. We Are Spirits [first stanza]: autograph manuscript poem, 1848 September 4., Page 33
  - Eliza Leslie: engraving, undated., Page 34
    Includes: Leslie, Eliza, 1787-1858. Autograph; United States Hotel, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1848 February 22.
  - Poore, Benjamin Perley, 1820-1887. Of Poets: autograph manuscript poem to Charles Henry Brainard, Indian Hill Farm near Newburyport, Massachusetts, 1848., Page 35
  - Dow, Jesse E. (Jesse Erskine), 1809-1850. Star of the brave whose sisters glow [first line]: autograph manuscript poem; Washington, D.C., 1848 January 28., Page 36
  - Hale, Sarah Josepha Buell, 1788-1879. While our faith in good grows stronger [first line]: autograph manuscript poem, undated., Page 37
  - Zschokke, Heinrich, 1771-1848. Letter to unidentified recipient., Page 38
    Written in German.
  - Multiple items., Page 39
    Channing, William F. (William Francis), 1820-1901. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard; Boston, Massachusetts, 1857 May 4.
    Channing, William Ellery, 1780-1842. Autograph.
  - Dawes, Rufus, 1803-1859. This is the hour of thought - when mind is free [first line]: autograph manuscript poem, undated., Page 40
  - Read, Thomas Buchanan, 1822-1872. Some Things Love Me: autograph manuscript poem, undated. Includes notation to Charles Henry Brainard., Page 42
  - Harrison, A.M. (Alexander Medina), 1829-1881. To Charlie: autograph manuscript poem; Washington D.C., 1847? December 25., Page 44
  - John Greenleaf Whittier: engraving, undated., Page 45
  - Willis, Nathaniel Parker, 1806-1867. Letter to Horatio Greenough, 1842 July 16., Page 46
  - Thomas Buchanan Read: engraving, undated., Page 47
  - Sparks, Jared, 1789-1866. Letter to Benjamin Perley Poore, 1847 October 25., Page 48
  - Lawrence, Abbott, 1792-1855. Letter to D.P. King?; Boston, Massachusetts, 1848 March 1?, Page 49
  - Multiple items., Page 50
    ?, Charles. Autograph, 1795 May 5.
    Hiller, Joseph, 1748-1814. Autograph.
    Lee, William Raymond, 1807-1891. Autograph.
    Hawthorne, Nathaniel, 1804-1864. Autograph.
  - George Lippard: engraving, undated., Page 52
    Includes: Lippard, George, 1822-1854. Autograph.
  - Orville Dewey: engraving, undated., Page 53
  - Dewey, Orville, 1794-1882. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard; New York, 1837 May? 24., Page 54
  - Eastburn, Manton, 1807-1872. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard; New York, 1837 May 18., Page 56
  - Simms, William Gilmore, 1806-1870. Letter to Solyman Brown; Charleston, South Carolina, 1837 May 28., Page 57
  - Headley, Joel Tyler, 1813-1897. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard; New York, 1848? February 22., Page 58
  - Everett, Edward, 1794-1865. Letter to George P. Marsh; Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1848 August 22., Page 59
  - Choate, Rufus, 1799-1859. Letter to unidentified recipient; Boston, Massachusetts, 1849 January 10., Page 60
  - Multiple items., Page 62
    Mathew, Theobald, 1790-1856. Autograph.
    Pencil sketch titled Yankee Doodle.
    Sketch titled Willard.
    Page has bottom portion torn away.
  - James, G.P.R. (George Payne Rainsford), 1801?-1860. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard; New York Hotel, New York, 1837 July 27., Page 63
  - Multiple items., Page 64
    Wallace, William Ross, 1819-1881. Excerpt from Alban, undated.
    Otis, Harrison Gray, 1765-1848. Letter to Charles Henry Brainard, 1845 June 6.
  - Fredrika Bremer: engraving, undated., Page 65
    Includes: Bremer, Fredrika, 1801-1865. Autograph.
  - Cary, Phoebe, 1824-1871. The Poem: autograph manuscript poem, undated., Page 66
    Also includes newspaper clipping of Cary's funeral.
  - Daniel Webster: engraving, undated., Page 67
  - Webster, Daniel, 1782-1852. Autograph note, undated., Page 68
  - Bache, A.D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867. Letter to J.R.?, 1848 June 18., Page 70
  - Multiple items., Page 71
    Scott, Winfield, 1786-1866. Letter to unidentified recipient; Washington D.C., 1852 September 15.
    Bancroft, George, 1800-1891. Letter to unidentified recipient, 1855 January.
  - Duffy, Charles Gavan, Sir, 1816-1903. Autograph., Page 72
  - Hagkill, D.H.? Autograph., Page 73
  - A Short History of Lorenzo Da Ponte's Life: autograph manuscript, undated., Page 74
  - John Sartain: engraving, undated., Page 75
  - Kean, Ellen, 1805-1880. Letter to unknown recipient, undated., Page 76
  - Burton, William E. (William Evans), 1802-1860. Letter to Foster?, 1851 July 5., Page 77
  - Multiple items., Page 78
    Newspaper clipping, obituary of Jacqueline S. Pendleton. 1859 April 12.
    Hope: autograph manuscript poem, undated.
    Pendleton, Jacqueline S. Autograph, 1858 March 15.
  - Multiple items., Page 80
    Hughes, John. Autograph.
    ?, Frank. Autograph.
  - Shillaber, B.P. (Benjamin Penhallow), 1814-1890. Letter written under the pen name Ruth Parington to an unidentified recipient, undated., Page 81
  - Irving, Washington, 1783-1859. Letter to William, New York, 1834 May 8., Page 82
    Signature has been cut out.
  - Bull, Ole, 1810-1880. Letter to unidentified recipient; Astor House, New York, 1875?, Page 84
  - Sully, Thomas, 1783-1872. Letter to Solyman Brown; Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1837 May 18., Page 85
  - Horace Greeley: engraving, undated., Page 87
    Includes: Greeley, Horace, 1811-1872. Autograph; New York, 1848 April 16.
  - Tupper, Martin Farquhar, 1810-1889. Autograph note; New York, 1851 May 23., Page 90
  - Prescott, William Hickling, 1796-1859. Autograph note, 1848 March 17., Page 106
  - Burritt, Elihu, 1810-1879. Letter to Horace Mann; London, England, 1851 February 14., Page 107
  - Multiple items., Page 113
    Nott, Eliphalet, 1773-1866. Autograph note.
    International Exchange logo.
    Vattemare, Alexandre, 1796-1864. Autograph; Washington, 1848 January 21.
  - Vermont Autograph and Remarker: pen printed newspaper, Huntington, Vermont, 1845 April 8., Page 116
    Possibly written by James Johns.
  - Marsh, George Perkins, 1801-1882. Letter to unknown recipient; Burlington, 1848 October 5., Page 118
  - Multiple items., Page 119
    Of all the poets of our time, [first line]: manuscript poem, undated.
    Kimball, J.F.? Autograph.
  - Kellogg, Miner K. (Miner Kilbourne), 1814-1899. Autograph, 1848 April 21., Page 127
  - Portrait of William Lloyd Garrison: advertisement., Page 129
  - Multiple items., Page 130
    Illegible autograph, includes address, Boston.
    Phelps, Charles A. (Charles Abner), 1820-1902. Autograph, includes address, Boston.
    Illegible autograph, includes address, Custom House.
    Sawyer, Warren. Autograph, includes address, 65 Kilby Street.
    Slack, Charles W. (Charles Wesley), 1825-1885. Autograph, includes address, W. Garland Street.
    Sewall, Samuel E. (Samuel Edmund), 1799-1888. Autograph, includes address, 46 Washington Street.
    Henshaw, Fred H. Autograph, includes address, 112 Washington Street.
    Hick, Amos? Autograph, includes address, Boston.
    Phillips, Wendell, 1811-1884. Autograph.
    Smith, Garrett, 1812-1892. Autograph.